# Ibrahim El-saeed Aboukhalil Accountant

**■** ibrahim.elsaeed83@gmail.com

01093254471

Al-Giza\_6october\_Zahraa New October

in linkedin.com/in/ibrahim-abou-khalil-7612761a5

## Career Objective

Professional Accounting Enthusiast with a strong commitment. Initiated preparation for the CMA Part one. Accountant wishes to take an active part in the business of the company, to be a part of success, to acquire scientific and practical experience, to keep pace with development, and to allow me to continue my career as an accountant in this entity.

#### Education

2018/10 - 2022/07

Bachelor's degree

Egypt

Faculty of Commerce English section

- Department: accounting and auditing.
- Grade: very good.
- Graduation project:on both odoo and spss.

2024/03 – present Nasr city, Egypt Oracle Digital accounting specialist

(Next Academy) ERP Career School

General Ledger Setup.

- Oracle Payables Setup.
- Accounts Receivables Setup.
- Cash Management Setup.
- Fixed Assets Setup.

2015/10 - 2018/07 Al-Beheira, Egypt General secondary education

Nasser Military Secondary School
• Grade: Excellent[92.3%]

### **Professional Experience**

2024/03 – present Sheikh Zayed, The Gate Plaza

#### JR Accountant AP and asset

Daltex corporation

- Registration of fixed assets: Documenting newly acquired fixed assets and ensuring that they are accurately recorded in the accounting system.
- Track existing assets: monitor and maintain records of existing fixed assets, tangible and intangible.
- •Monitor the capitalization of assets and de-recognition in accordance with the company's policy and accounting standards.
- •Calculate depreciation and amortization expenses and ensure proper recording in the financial statements.
- Maintain and update the fixed assets register, and ensure accurate recording of acquisitions, transfers and disposals.
- Manage sales orders and purchase orders within the global shared services framework.
- Allocate logistics costs efficiently and accurately.
- Process invoices and ensure timely settlement of invoices/orders.
- Responsible for closing the fixed assets and depreciation unit and ensuring the completion of the trial balance.
- -P2P Responsibility:
- Invoice processing and discount notes.
- Keep vendor master data up to date
- Analyze vendor accounts, resolve negative balances and reconcile seller data.

- Prepare the payment proposal according to the agreed calendar, ensuring its correctness and respecting deadlines.
- quality and performance, meeting the specified KPIs within the P2P department.
- Handle non-automated fellow expenses in oracle.
- Validate and review automated expense coding.
- Colleagues requested currency advances and settlement of related expenses.
- Responsible for generating payments (scheduled and urgent).
- Ensure that all payments have been signed by authorized signatories and that Treasury has been notified of payment amounts prior to operations.
- General ledger maintenance for procurement and reporting.
- Upload and process invoices/payment request forms.
- Maintenance and matching of purchase orders.
- Manage exceptions on purchase orders.
- Manage business rules in Vendor Invoice Management (VIM) for purchase order invoices and non-purchase orders.
- Make sure you have the e-invoice and apply the correct VAT and WHT.
- Reconcile and ensure that all invoices are recorded in the system.
- Prepare monthly dues and ensure their accuracy.
- Timely claim discounts and ensure that publication is not delayed.
- Follow-up and application of discounts according to agreements.
- Ensure proper coding of invoices to appropriate general ledger accounts.
- Assist with month-end and year-end closures by ensuring that all A/P transactions are accurately recorded.
- Cheque Preparation .
- Other administrative tasks such as daily review of our bank status and modification of the seller's

account when making a payment.

- Manage the day-to-day cash position to balance inflows and outflows within the organization.
- Process and enter invoices into the accounting system in a timely manner.

### **Internships**

2023/11 - 2024/02

Rotografia group

SAP end user

Sheikh zayed, Capital Business

Account payable -Account receivable -cash payment and received-GS1-Portal

2021/11 - 2022/06

Rotografia group

Sheikh zaved,

Cost accountant and control

Capital Business

- Cost accountant (Job order system- ABC system).
- Tracing and applied OH.
- pricing and inventory management.
- Joint cost and JIT.

2020/10 - 2021/03

Rotografia group

Sheikh zayed,

Sales local

Capital Business

- Negotiation skills.
- Familiarity with the nature of the company's activity, the nature of the Packaging industry, and the stages of operation to provide correct, effective, and quick answers to the customer.
- Participation in company exhibitions

2019/07 - 2020/01

Internal control

6october\_Degla,

• Inventory control, additions and receipts.

Mechanical and building foundations company

Zahraa New October

• Periodic inventory of stores.

• Control over the percentage of completion of construction in accordance with the contracts concluded for subcontractors.

### Courses

Oline

2024/01 CMA PART1 | In progress |

Dr/ Abdalla abdelnaim{Holder of CPA,CMA,CFM,CIA,CRMA,CISA,CFE,IPSAS Diploma,COSO IC

- ERM certIFR,CertIA,CertIPSAS,GRCA certificates}

2024/03 – present Naser city, Egypt Freelance

EYouth

- Career planning Simulation of portfolio building
- Emotional intelligence
- Unique selling points- Budgeting, pricing and how to write proposals
- Final project
- Virtual presentation skills
- Recruitment coach
- Freelance

## Languages

## **English**

Writing Level B2Listening Level B2Speaking Level B2